Our planet is heating up due to something called the greenhouse effect.
我们的星球正因所谓的温室效应而不断升温。
This is one of the reasons why Earth is seeing more extreme weather events, such as heatwaves, forest fires and floods each year.
这也是地球每年出现更多极端天气事件（如热浪、森林火灾和洪水）的原因之一。
But what exactly is the greenhouse effect, and what can we do to reduce it?
但温室效应到底是什么？我们又能做些什么来缓解它？
Let's first think about a greenhouse – you may have one in your garden!
我们先想想温室——你家的花园里说不定就有一个！
It's a glass structure that protects plants against low temperatures by trapping heat inside.
它是一种玻璃结构，通过将热量困在内部来保护植物抵御低温。
But, while this helps your plants grow, Earth is trapping heat in the same way, and it's causing global warming.
虽然这种机制有助于植物生长，但地球正以同样的方式锁住热量，而这正在引发全球变暖。
When fossil fuels, such as coal, oil and gas, are burnt for power, carbon dioxide is released as a waste product.
当煤炭、石油、天然气等化石燃料被燃烧发电时，会释放出二氧化碳这种废弃物。
It enters the atmosphere and acts like a blanket around the planet, which means heat radiation can't escape and the temperature increases.
它进入大气层，像一层毯子包裹住地球，导致热辐射无法散出，进而造成气温上升。
The impact of gases on the Earth's climate was first investigated in the 1820s.
气体对地球气候的影响早在19世纪20年代就首次被研究。
Eunice Foote, a scientist and women's rights activist, tested the effects of sunlight on different gases that she put into glass cylinders.
科学家兼女权活动家尤妮斯·富特将不同气体装入玻璃圆筒，测试了阳光对这些气体的影响。
Her results showed that carbon dioxide traps heat more than other gases.
她的研究结果表明，二氧化碳比其他气体的锁热能力更强。
The idea of the greenhouse effect was born.
温室效应的概念就此诞生。
So, what can we do to reduce the greenhouse effect?
那么，我们能做些什么来缓解温室效应？
The UN recommends using more energy-efficient electrical appliances at home and switching to LED lightbulbs.
联合国建议，在家中使用更节能的电器，更换为LED灯泡。
Also, by washing your clothes at 30° instead of a higher temperature, around 40% less electricity is used over a year, according to the Energy Saving Trust.
此外，英国节能信托基金会的数据显示，用30摄氏度的水温洗衣服，而非更高的温度，一年能减少约40%的用电量。
A change in diet is also something to consider.
饮食结构的改变也值得考虑。
The charity A Well-Fed World, claim that plant-based foods, as opposed to meat and dairy, need less land and water to be produced.
慈善机构“丰饶世界”称，与肉类和乳制品相比，生产植物性食物所需的土地和水资源更少。
So, switching saves energy and lowers emissions, which contribute to climate change.
因此，调整饮食结构能节约能源，减少导致气候变化的温室气体排放。
We only have one planet, so let's try and take care of it as much as we can.
我们只有一个地球，所以请尽我们所能去爱护它。